[{"id":2,"tema":"Plástico","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many plastic pieces can we find in 2,5km2 of ocean?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"5.000 pieces","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"46.000 pieces","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"there are'nt pieces of in the ocean, crazy","correcta":false}]},{"id":3,"tema":"Plástico","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many plastic bags are recycled across the world?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"50%","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"100%","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Less than a 5%","correcta":true}]},{"id":4,"tema":"Plástico","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many years does it take for a plastic container to decompose?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Up to 10.000 years","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Up to 1.000 years","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"Up to 1.000.000 years","correcta":false}]},{"id":5,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How much has the concentration of CO2 augmented during the last 200 years?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"A 33%","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"A 75%","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"on the contrary, pollution has decreased","correcta":false}]},{"id":6,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"At which temperature does ice transform into liquid?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"When we get close to 30ºC it starts to fall apart","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Over 0ºC","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"at 100ºC it is still hard","correcta":false}]},{"id":7,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many of the 18 hottest years of history were in the XXI century?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"3","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"18","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"17","correcta":true}]},{"id":8,"tema":"Agua","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What is the % of fresh water of the total water on the planet?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"The 0.01%","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"The 25%","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"The 3%","correcta":true}]},{"id":9,"tema":"Agua","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What is the % of drinking water of the total water on the planet?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"All the water on the planet is drinkable","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"0,007%","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"3%","correcta":false}]},{"id":10,"tema":"Agua","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Is it important to save water from the shower or with the toilet chain?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Yes, because my mom doesn't scold me.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Not since there is a lot of water","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Yes, since it is a scarce good","correcta":true}]},{"id":11,"tema":"Bosque","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What happens if we burn or cut down the forests and rainforests?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Decreases the capacity to transform CO2 into O2","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"Nothing, because there are many trees","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"That we ran out of places to go on excursions","correcta":false}]},{"id":12,"tema":"Bosque","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many spices of the world total live in the rainforests?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"95% of the total","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"15% of the total","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Half of the living spices we know","correcta":true}]},{"id":13,"tema":"Plástico","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many plastic bags are being used every minute?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"10.000.000.000","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"1.000.000","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"25","correcta":false}]},{"id":14,"tema":"Plástico","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many petrol liters are needed to make 1000 plastic bottles?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"91 liters","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"1 liter","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"36 liters","correcta":false}]},{"id":15,"tema":"Plástico","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Which % of plastic is possible to recycle?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Plastic is not recyclable","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"95%","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"62%","correcta":false}]},{"id":16,"tema":"Plástico","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Where would you throw the plastic and tetrapack containers?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"To the yellow container.","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"To the blue container.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"To the ground, which is why there are street sweeper","correcta":false}]},{"id":17,"tema":"Agua","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many days can a person live without drinking water?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"2 weeks.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Less than a day.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Between 5 and 7 days","correcta":true}]},{"id":18,"tema":"Agua","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Is water a finite resource?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Yes","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"No, there is much as we think","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Hot water only","correcta":false}]},{"id":19,"tema":"Agua","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many people around the world do not have access to potable water?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"250 people","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"1100 million people","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"7500 million people","correcta":false}]},{"id":20,"tema":"Agua","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many litres of water could we pollute by throwing 4 litres of gasoline within them?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"200.000 liters","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"650.000 liters","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"2.800.000 liters","correcta":true}]},{"id":21,"tema":"Agua","idioma":"English","pregunta":"In a 100 year period, a water drop spends...","respuestas":[{"respuesta":" 20 months in the ocean, 98 years in ice state, 2 weeks in a lake and rivers and less than a week in the atmosphere","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"2 weeks in the ocean, 20 months in ice state, 98 years in a lake and rivers and less than a week in the atmosphere","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"98 years in the ocean, 20 months in ice state, 2 weeks in a lake and rivers and less than a week in the atmosphere","correcta":true}]},{"id":22,"tema":"Agua","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many litres of water are needed to make a 1L plastic bottle?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"80L","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"2L","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"1L","correcta":false}]},{"id":23,"tema":"Bosque","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Between which tropics do we find tropical jungles and forests?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Sagittarius and Leo","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Cancer and Capricorn","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"Madagascar and Chile","correcta":false}]},{"id":24,"tema":"Bosque","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Why are the forests and tropical jungles so important?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"To be able to record beautiful documentaries","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"To be able to extract the rubber.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"They stabilize the weather and give us O2 that is needed to live in our planet","correcta":true}]},{"id":25,"tema":"Bosque","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many tropical forest’s hectares did we lose in 2018?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"About 12 million hectares, the same size as Nicaragua","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"About 64 million hectares, the same size as France","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"About 47 thousand hectares, the same size as Andorra","correcta":false}]},{"id":26,"tema":"Bosque","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Which’s the world’s largest tropical sib in the world?Selvas de China y Hainan","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Montseny","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Amazonas","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"Jungles of China and Hainan","correcta":false}]},{"id":27,"tema":"Bosque","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many trees around the world are cut down daily to produce toilet paper?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"1 tree","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"4800 trees","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"27000 trees","correcta":true}]},{"id":28,"tema":"Residuos","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many tons of waste are produced by one person throughout his life?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"90 tons","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"1600 tons","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"4200 tons","correcta":false}]},{"id":29,"tema":"Residuos","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many Kg of waste do we individually produce daily?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"0.5 kg","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"2 kg","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"1.2 kg","correcta":false}]},{"id":30,"tema":"Residuos","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many times can a can be recycled?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"About 200 times","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Aluminum cannot be recycled","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Infinite times","correcta":true}]},{"id":31,"tema":"Residuos","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How much energy can we produce by recycling 3 glass bottles?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"The necessary to charge a phone during a whole year","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"The necessary to make a TV work 50 years","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"The one needed to turn on a light bulb for one hour","correcta":false}]},{"id":32,"tema":"Residuos","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What do we have to do with the waste we can’t recycle (batteries, phones, electric devices…)?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Throw them in the grey container","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Take them to a green dot","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"Leave them on the tree in front of my house","correcta":false}]},{"id":33,"tema":"Residuos","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What type of waste is mainly produced by a person?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Plastic containers","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Glass containers","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Organic waste","correcta":true}]},{"id":34,"tema":"Residuos","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What can we obtain by recycling the organic faction?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Energy","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"Worms for the birds","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Nothing good","correcta":false}]},{"id":35,"tema":"Residuos","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What’s the best way to take care of our planet?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Reuse products and objects","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Reduce waste. Less consumption and more conscious.","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"Recycle waste","correcta":false}]},{"id":36,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How long does it take for the sun to irradiate the same amount of energy that is used by the humanity in one year?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"17 days","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"38 seconds","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"15 minutes","correcta":true}]},{"id":37,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How intense must be de wind to produce wind power?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"15 km/h","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"45 km/h","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"250 km/h","correcta":false}]},{"id":38,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What does CO2 that is produced in thermal power plants cause to the environment?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"More beautiful and clearer skies at night.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Acid rain and global warming.","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"Extra energy to run vehicles","correcta":false}]},{"id":39,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What type of residues are generated in nuclear power stations?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Nucleic acids.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Only the plastics and containers that workers throw away.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Radioactive waste","correcta":true}]},{"id":40,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many planets Earth would be needed to keep with the current consummation rate?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"1,75 planets","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"The one we have is already enough.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"3 planets","correcta":false}]},{"id":41,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Which amount of energy can be saved by changing every light bulb into an energy saving one?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"3%","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"75%","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"With the price they have you don't save anything","correcta":false}]},{"id":42,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What’s the highest recommended temperature to program the heating at home?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"35ºC to be able to go with flip-flops around the house.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"10ºC and put on a sweater, a blanket, a scarf and drink hot drinks.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"20ºC and go with a small sweater","correcta":true}]},{"id":43,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What’s the lowest recommended temperature to program the air conditioner at home?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"26ºC and go lightly of clothes","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"15ºC and wear a scarf and a long shirt","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"35ºC and combine it with a fan","correcta":false}]},{"id":44,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How many Kw are consumed yearly by all the plugged in (and turned off) devices?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"If they are off, they do not consume anything.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"400 KW","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"125 KW","correcta":false}]},{"id":45,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How much money do we pay because of all the devices that are plugged in even if we don’t use them?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Between 15 and 25 cents.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"If they are turned off they do not consume and therefore you do not pay.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Up to 5 euros","correcta":true}]},{"id":46,"tema":"Energía","idioma":"English","pregunta":"How is petrol transported through the different countries around the world?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"There is no need to transport it since it is extracted in each country that needs it.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"In helicopters.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Trough the sea using tankers","correcta":true}]},{"id":47,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What happens if the planet’s temperature is increased?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"That in winter we won't have to put the heating on.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Spices will live in a more pleasant climate.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"The climate becomes more extreme and difficult to prevent","correcta":true}]},{"id":48,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Does eating animal’s meat have an impact in our climate?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Yes, due to the gases that these animals emit during their digestion.","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"No, this way there are fewer animals eating the plants and trees.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"There is no relationship.","correcta":false}]},{"id":49,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Why do polluting gases heat our planet?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Because they come out of chimneys that are at high temperatures","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"They trap the heat produced by the sun and then act like a blanket for the planet.","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"They don't heat it but cool it","correcta":false}]},{"id":50,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Who transforms CO2 into Oxygen?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"People when they burn fossil fuels.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Cows when they breathe.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"The organisms of the plant kingdom","correcta":true}]},{"id":51,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"Why are the polar ice caps so important?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"They act as a mirror, the hot light that comes from the sun hits them and gets rejected.","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"To be able to take out ice to make the refreshments in summer.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"They are not so much, since almost nobody lives.","correcta":false}]},{"id":52,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What’s one reason of climate changing?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"The fumes from the volcanoes when they erupt.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"The gases that produce the greenhouse effect.","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"It is an inevitable natural cycle","correcta":false}]},{"id":53,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What’s sustainable development?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"The development that recycles all the waste it generates","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"The one that satisfies all our needs.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"That which satisfices the present generation’s necessities without involving the future ones.","correcta":true}]},{"id":54,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What causes an oil spill at sea when an oil tanker accident occurs?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"Nothing, since the oil seeps into the sea bed and returns to where it came from.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"Environmental disasters with the death of fish, sea birds, microscopic animals...","correcta":true},{"respuesta":"Dirty waters that must be cleaned before bathing","correcta":false}]},{"id":55,"tema":"Contaminación","idioma":"English","pregunta":"What is the best way to move around the territory?","respuestas":[{"respuesta":"By motorcycle, because you can get there very quickly.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"In a helicopter, you can save on traffic jams and park on the roof.","correcta":false},{"respuesta":"By public transport","correcta":true}]}]